At last, we have it now,
a robot to kill Godzilla.
The year is 1992 A.D.
In order to counter the threat posed
to the planet's survival by Godzilla,
Japan's Counter G Bureau
recruited the world's
most brilliant
scientific minds to build
a fighting machine.
The first machine was called "Garuda."
But its fighting
capabilities were limited.
A far more powerful
machine was required.
They salvaged a robot from the future,
Mecha-King Ghidorah,
in order to study its
advanced technology.
They applied technology of
numerous anti-personnel weapons
and created the mightiest machine to
attack Godzilla called "Mechagodzilla."
Its main engine is a reactor.
It uses a derivative of heavy
hydrogen helium three in pellet form.
The armor is a heatproof alloy,
codenamed NT-1.
And what about the protective shield?
Synthetic diamond,
it's totally heat-repellent.
It reflects the heat
back to the source.
That's incredible.
I really believe this machine is
the weapon to defeat Godzilla.
Oh, shit.
Hi, I'd like you to
meet Yuri Katagiri.
Hi there. I'm Kazuma Aoki.
So this is Robot One?
Yeah.
It's the ultimate in modern technology,
otherwise known as Garuda.
Was the ultimate, now it's just junk.
Kazu here was on the team
that built this machine.
Of course he thinks...
So where do you work?
This section.
You do, do you?
Well, then, welcome aboard.
Not quite.
You've just been transferred.
- What?
- Look.
"Mr. Kazuma Aoki is to report
immediately to G-force."
G-force?
Single, with no children.
- Hobbies, pteranodons?
- Right, sir.
Don't you know what they are, sir?
They're small flying dinosaurs.
Enough. You have been
transferred over here
to take part in the Robot Two project
together with three ace pilots.
But I'm starting to have my doubts.
I'm wondering if there hasn't
been some kind of mistake.
Flying dinosaurs!
I don't know where you think you are.
This isn't a summer camp
for dinosaur freaks.
It's a training center.
Do you understand?
- Yes, sir.
- Come in.
Sonezaki reporting for duty, sir.
Take him and drill him.
Ready.
Start.
Goddammit, I've lost all
power in sector two.
We were up here with the
Russians doing a geological
survey for their
national petroleum guys.
And we came across something strange,
instead of petroleum.
Professor, is this
really a pteranodon?
Yes, I'm certain.
That's not all, we found an egg.
Show me where.
That's incredible.
I just can't believe it.
A pteranodon egg.
And it would seem to
be perfectly intact.
Look at it, it's enormous!
Professor, what do you
think this could be?
Azusa, come here. Take a look at this.
- It's a plant substance.
- Could it be some kind of fern?
Professor, look at the egg.
Look!
What the hell is that?
- Rodan.
- Rodan?
It's a giant pteranodon.
- You think it's from that other egg?
- I'm certain. It's been irradiated.
That's why it's so enormous.
The same thing happened to Godzilla.
You know, this whole island
is a junkyard of nuclear waste.
Godzilla!
Back to the helicopter.
The giant pteranodon egg found on
Adonoa Island has been taken to Kyoto.
It will be examined by Professor Omae
of the National Institute of Biotechnics.
Right now, the question being
asked is, "Will the egg hatch?"
Wow, that's incredible.
"National Institute of Biotechnics"
A 65-million-year-old egg right here.
Amazing!
- What are you doing?
- Hello there.
My name is...
Who are you? Do you work here?
No. I'm a pteranodon enthusiast.
Excuse me.
Hey, wait. You can't come in here.
It's off-limits.
That's okay, don't worry.
This is really most interesting.
You can't stay here.
Tell me. You think it'll hatch?
That would be a gas.
Just imagine it.
- Tell me, what are these?
- Don't touch them!
Yes?
Yes, I'll be right there.
All right, Professor.
- Please get out.
- Maybe I'll say hello to the professor.
Out of the question.
Right.
Okay.
But this was meant to happen.
What?
What I mean to say is who knows
what it might lead to, you and me...
If you continue,
you're gonna get a slap in the face.
I didn't mean to...
Here are the photographs of
constant surveillance on the egg.
Day and night, one frame
per hour for a week.
The color seems to be changing.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
I guess it must have
dropped into my pocket.
I'll bring it back as soon as I can.
I don't believe a word
you're telling me!
If you ask me, you stole it from here.
Bring it back right now or else.
So I'm a thief now, huh?
Azusa, wanna hear my theory
about our egg here?
Sure.
The egg's color indicates how it's
feeling at the time, I think.
When we took it from its nest
on the island, it turned red.
Because it was afraid.
It turns red whenever
it's afraid or distressed.
I see.
Azusa, I checked your
duty hours for last week.
I found that whenever you were away,
the egg turned bright red.
Otherwise, it stayed a normal color.
- Look here.
- But why would it do that?
It's listening to outside sounds,
in hopes that maybe
it'll recognize its
mother's voice somewhere.
That's my theory anyway.
But instead of her,
Azusa, it heard you.
Hey, what's this?
It's a prehistoric plant. Pretty old.
Yes, I can feel it.
"Mental Development Center"
- Hello, Miki.
- Hello.
- How are you, Miki?
- Fine.
- Nice to see you. Are you well?
Well, I never! This is a surprise.
- Hello, sir. It's lovely to see you again.
- You too.
- And who's this?
- Aoki, G-force, sir.
G-force, did you say?
I don't trust you guys one little bit.
Please, sir, we need your assistance.
Can you take a look?
It emits something strange,
but it's very weak.
We can't seem to measure it.
Maybe they could find what it is.
- Music?
- That's right, listen.
The children felt it
when they concentrated,
then fed it into the computer.
Yes? What? What's that?
What we've got is no pteranodon.
This baby is something else!
It's...
- it's a Godzillasaur.
- What's a Godzillasaur?
It's in the Godzilla family,
but this species is not as aggressive.
Really? You sure?
Well, he looks inoffensive.
He's kind of cute, isn't he?
Well, one thing's certain,
this is no Godzilla.
What we have here is a
plant-eating Godzillasaur.
Yeah.
I wonder...
Maybe the egg was a parasite egg.
- What?
- Professor, what's a parasite egg?
Well, it's like some birds.
They lay their eggs in the
nests of other birds.
For example, the European cuckoo.
What?
Godzilla.
Yes?
What's that?
Godzilla's attacking the city?
- Where's Kazuma?
- I don't know.
What? Where the hell is that jackass?
Chase, get me a backup pilot.
All systems green.
You see, Mechagodzilla is stronger.
See, it can return your heat beam.
We've got you, Godzilla.
What's that?
The power discharge.
It's flowing backwards, sir.
Go after him!
Things aren't looking good, I'm afraid.
It'll take weeks to fix Mechagodzilla.
Damn!
I hope we're not too late.
Son of a bitch!
What's going on? Where's he heading?
Due west, sir.
Kyoto?
He must be stopped, whatever the cost.
He's through our defenses.
So, what will we do?
It appears to be destroying
everything in its path.
It's unstoppable.
There are explosions and massive
fires all over the city.
Someone has to do something,
or Kyoto will be destroyed.
Now it looks like it's heading
for the Kyoto Tower.
Evacuate the building.
Get out! Godzilla's coming!
Professor, do you think
the baby called it?
"National Institute of Biotechnics"
Do you have a sealed room here?
Maybe we can isolate the baby.
If we can stop it calling,
there's a chance that we...
We can stop Godzilla.
Azusa, we could try the
underground cell store.
I think that Godzilla went
to the island for a reason.
I think it went there to
collect the Godzillasaur egg.
Godzilla's up there.
He's above us!
Don't be afraid.
He's gone away.
"Godzilla Left to Osaka Bay"
Well, I...
You see, sir, I just used up a few days'
vacation I had coming to me, sir.
Well, next time, ask my permission
first before you go taking vacations.
I mean it.
Do you understand?
Well, let's just forget it this time.
Catch.
"Starting June 29, Officer Kazuma will
be in charge of the parking lot."
That's what it says, Kazuma.
Now get out. Goodbye.
Come in.
Excuse me, sir.
What, you mean, you?
Baby.
You can't still be hungry.
You've only just eaten.
Well, just a little bit, then.
Here.
It's really perfect.
He'll love it here.
We'll raise it here,
but we'll need your assistance.
We'll all be counting on you,
miss, I hope you realize.
Don't worry, sir.
Take good care of it.
As you well know,
it's a very important animal.
Welding team to sector three.
And also, check that
transducer coupling.
Professor Omae of the
National Institute of
Biotechnics has come up
with a startling discovery.
It would seem that the
Godzillasaur in captivity
has a second brain
located in its body.
Right here.
So therefore the same
must be true with Godzilla.
- Correct.
- Go on, sir.
We'll change Mechagodzilla's attack plan,
to attack this weak point.
Next time, we'll attack from behind
and aim for his second brain.
This new attack plan has
been given a code name,
G-crusher.
It'll paralyze Godzilla completely.
Without that brain,
he won't be able to stand up.
Baby, what are you doing?
Come here immediately.
Hey, babe.
What is that?
This is my new limousine.
And you can cut out
the "babe" business.
I'm sorry. What's that?
He's playing as usual.
Baby, you be good, okay?
You got promoted?
Yes, I did. I'm back flying again.
I'm really glad.
What's that?
This is my new robot.
It's called pteranodon.
And, yes, it can fly.
- Can it really?
- Why not come for a ride?
Take this. I think it should fit.
Hold on to me.
Baby!
You know, I pity your future husband.
He's gonna be a real handful.
Just think. You'll need at least a
mansion to house your dinosaur.
Yeah.
Right, here we go.
Oh, my God.
This way, girls.
Can I help you?
The girls wanted to come and see Baby.
- Are they all from the ESP school?
- Yes.
- Hello, miss.
- Hello there.
Isn't he lovely?
- He's still only little, though.
- Yeah, he is so little.
The girls have learned
to sing a song for him.
- Really?
- Girls, sing for Baby.
Yes, please. Go on.
All right.
- Baby!
- What?
Baby, what's the matter?
No, Baby.
I don't understand.
What's the matter with him?
What's wrong?
Yes, that must be it.
It must be the song.
The song?
You remember.
The last time we heard the music,
the baby started to hatch out.
Whenever he hears the plant's music,
Baby somehow gets a
huge intake of power.
The aim of the plan is to somehow
try to lure Godzilla away.
The destination,
the Ogasawara Islands.
They're remote and uninhabited.
And the only way to lure
Godzilla is with a decoy.
And what will you use?
We've no alternative.
The Godzillasaur.
Baby's life can't be put at risk.
Don't worry.
You'll be looking after him.
I've decided that for this mission,
you'll be on board the Mechagodzilla.
- But what for?
- Because, my dear,
I need you to find the exact
location of that second brain.
Believe me, it's very important.
I beg you, stop this operation.
I understand your concern, miss.
This dinosaur is an important asset.
It would be foolish to waste it.
Baby's not an asset.
He's just an intelligent
being with a right to live.
Baby's not a commodity
or a disposable asset.
Wait a moment.
The men of G-force
have a responsibility.
They must rid the world of the
threat posed by Godzilla.
That's why they've got to
go ahead with this plan.
I'm sorry if you can't accept that.
You know, I did think...
that fighting Godzilla was doing
something worthwhile for humankind.
But now I guess I've
just changed my mind.
Baby did that for you, I think.
I feel sorry for Baby.
I guess he was born 65
million years too late.
Maybe. Or else too early.
Why too early?
Well, dinosaurs were around
for 150 million years,
and man has only been around
for two million years.
Who knows,
one day dinosaurs could
make a comeback.
Come on.
All right.
Look, it's frightened.
Baby.
Sorry, miss, you'll have to come down.
I'll stay here.
- Please close the door.
- You sure?
Baby needs somebody.
This is all I could do.
All right, close it up.
Baby.
Don't be afraid.
I'll look after you.
It's all right now.
This is Lizard One, course 167.
Roger.
What time is the attack
scheduled to begin?
In 30 minutes, at 1700.
A report from Chitose Base, sir.
A giant bird was sighted
above Amori 10 minutes ago.
A giant bird? Like what?
We have visual contact.
What the hell?
It's Rodan.
- Rodan?
- Rodan's alive. Look!
The giant bird is now heading west.
Sendai's had a sighting.
It's now turned south.
Where's it going?
Maybe...
Listen, the baby's
eyes were glowing red.
It could've been an SOS.
Baby is, after all,
Rodan's half-brother.
They're communicating.
Contact Lizard One immediately.
Roger, returning to base, over.
Baby!
Lizard One, come in.
Goddamn it!
Kazuma, the container's gone missing.
It's me, sir.
- Who's "me"?
- Aoki, sir.
I'm sorry, sir, I had to do it.
Garuda was my idea, sir.
Sir, Rodan's landed!
Hurry! Rodan's landed.
He's breaking open the container.
Oh, no!
There they are.
- That's a heat beam.
- Same as Godzilla's.
- Plasma grenades?
- Wait. Aoki!
We're gonna use plasma.
You distract Rodan.
Get him clear of that box!
Roger.
Damn that Rodan!
Hurry!
- Where are you?
- Hurry! Come on!
- Quick!
- Azusa, are you okay?
Yes, sir. We're both all right.
Baby's fine too.
Get down, Professor. We'll open it.
Cut it open.
Godzilla's here at last.
The energy pool's overheated, sir.
We can't run it.
Shit!
Aoki, come get us, hurry!
Damn!
Hurry! Godzilla's here. Aoki!
Godzilla?
All right!
You got here just in time.
I was getting worried.
Well, where were you?
Off on another vacation?
Let's see if you can get
that tin can upright.
Let's go!
Roger.
Super Mechagodzilla ready to go.
Do exactly as you were told.
Do you hear?
Do it. You have to.
We got Godzilla.
At long last we've won.
We've done it, Commander!
Sorry, sir. Roger and out.
Aoki, where are you going?
Azusa, it's me!
Are you all right? Azusa!
Yes, we're all right.
All right, finish it.
Baby.
Rodan is still alive.
What's that power?
That is Rodan's energy.
Godzilla's second brain
is regenerating.
What's that?
It's Rodan's energy.
It revived the brain.
My God.
That isn't possible.
Incredible.
The armor's going, sir.
Hold on to your helmets.
We're not beaten yet.
You're wrong. There are plenty of us.
Azusa, Kazuma, hurry.
Baby,
you must leave.
You must go back with the others.
It's the only way. Can't you see that?
Baby,
I can't look after you anymore. See?
I'm so sorry.
Baby.
I can't stay.
You have to understand.
And thank you, Baby.
Take care, now.
Miki, this is Azusa.
Do you read me? Over.
Please, Miki.
Try to make Godzilla understand,
try using your telepathy,
that he must take Baby away.
He doesn't belong here.
Do you think you'll be
able to do that, Miki?
Yes, I'll try.
There's proof for all that
life always conquers.
Life, sir?
Reptiles or humankind,
we all fight to protect our offspring.
Take care, now, Baby.
You as well, Godzilla.
Will there be a
dinosaur age long after
man's presence here
has been forgotten?
It will come, I'm sure.
It may not be for another
few million years.
I also know...
they'll be waiting for it.